# Samuel Marks

206.601.9523 samuelmarks81@gmail.com

### **Profile**

I have over four years of experience studying, researching, and designing brilliant and intuitive user experiences. I have a background in art and music and a persisting interest in these subjects that led me to study Human Centered Design & Engineering with a focus in Human-Computer Interaction at the UW in Seattle, Washington.

Through various roles in UX design, user research, design consultation and film production I have continued to gain knowledge and refine skills in user research, user journey mapping, interaction design, UX/UI design, information architecture, and communicating design work and findings to stakeholders and leadership.

## **Work Experience**

#### UX Designer, Amazon via Fiduciary Tech; Bellevue, WA - Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

At Fiduciary Tech, I conducted user research and usability testing, and created wireframes, hi-fidelity mockups, and interactive prototypes for the redesign of an internal web-application used by 10,000+ users across 10 countries. Other responsibilities included information architecture and interaction design, data analysis, and presentations.

**UX Design Contractor, Samuel Marks Design; Lake Stevens, WA — Nov. 2015 - Present**I currently provide user research, user experience design, usability testing and data analysis to clients through private contracts. Common deliverables include field studies, competitive analyses, heuristic evaluations, user personas, journey maps, information architecture, wireframes, mockups, interactive prototypes, design specifications, usability tests, data analyses, and reports.

#### UX Designer II, Whiting House Group; Lenexa, KS — Oct. 2016 - Dec. 2017

While at Whiting House I helped to standardize many aspects of our user experience practice, especially in the area of interaction design where I created Axure and InVision libraries for our team to share. Through this experience, I was able to communicate exceptional experiences to both stakeholders and users.

#### UX/UI Consultant, Design JMB; Redmond, WA — Sept. 2016 - Oct 2016

While working for Design JMB, I collaborated with stakeholders and clients to elicit design requirements. I also designed and prototyped UI/UX design solutions using Axure, Sketch, and Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator and communicated, negotiated, and justified intelligent design decisions to stakeholders and clients.

### Education

**University of Washington, Seattle, WA** — Bachelor of Science: Human Centered Design & Engineering: Human-Computer Interaction, Spring 2016

### **Skills**

User Experience Design, Interaction Design, User Research, Usability Testing, Hi-Fi & Lo-Fi Prototyping, 3D Prototyping, Data Visualization, Mobile App Design, Video Production, Persona Development, User Journey Mapping, Writing, Familiar with HTML/CSS/JavaScript.

# <u>Tools</u>

Sketch, InVision, Axure, Zeplin, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, InDesign, PowerPoint, Power BI, Tableau, Microsoft Excel & Office Suite.

#### Links

http://www.samuelmarksdesign.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-marks-71562bb1/

# **Additional Information**

- COMMUNICATION Thorough Detail Oriented Active Listener
- LEADERSHIP Team Individual
- WEB TRENDS User Centered Responsive
- PROBLEM-SOLVING Critical Thinker Asks Questions Validates Assumptions
- TIME MANAGEMENT Agile